### **BEN WHITE**

benjaminwhite@live.co.uk 07592 076164

github.com/benjamin-white workbyben.com

## **ABOUT ME**

I have worked professionally for five years as a full stack web developer. Prior to my current role I worked in retail management but a long time passion for code drove me to finally make the switch in 2016 after attending a bootcamp with the aim of expanding my knowledge. I am generally thoughful and patient but decisive where and when needed. I like to find fun in challenges and feel value in knowing what I do contributes to a business's overall success.

Other than coding my interests are 3D graphics (viewable here behance.net/nvlnvl), finding great music, reading books and going to the park with my family.

### **KEY SKILLS**

- + Javascript, PHP and SQL
- + React (class based and v16+ hooks)
- + I write semantic HTML and cross browser SASS/CSS
- + Custom Webpack setups and transpiling with Babel
- + Experience with a range of popular frontend libraries, eg. Lodash, D3, Fuse, ThreeJS
- + Consuming and writing RESTful APIs and working with GraphQL
- + Applying SOLID principles within OOP
- + SEO optimisation techniques
- + Apache, CRON and DNS configuration
- + Git and Gitflow
- + Experience writing unit and feature tests and following the Red/Green/Refactor methodology

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Senior Developer at sixtwo.tech from 2016 to present

Currently I work for a Kent based but remote first web agency. The role is full stack; writing server and client side code, making and implementing infrastructure decisions and managing DNS for our clients. I provide support to other developers with feedback in code reviews and 1 to 1 catch-ups, help unblock them on technical and architectural roadblocks and guide on best practice. I co-ordinate closely with design to ensure we arrive at UI and UX solutions that meet accesibility requirements and SEO performance. I collaborate with project management by quoting on projects, giving advice on feasibility and helping to refine requirements. This partnership helps to ensure projects can be delivered on time and meet or surpass expectations. The core platform we have been working with is Wordpress alongside Advanced Custom Fields while headless Gutenberg and a React frontend is where we're going at the moment.

One of my projects was the original build and later rebrand of a multisite of seven regions two of which have ecommerce, <u>playshufl.com</u>. A unique challenge of this build was synchronising content between the sites. I would be happy to share more projects I have built on request.

I enjoy my current role but want to stretch myself with new challenges building on the knowldege and experience that I have.

Deputy Manager at Iceland Foods from 2006 to 2016

I was involved with all aspects of the business such as legal compliance, creation of rotas and staff reviews. I actively sought ownership of business KPIs, seeing where I could make a positive impact and then pursuing the responsibility to do so. I particularly enjoyed increasing team engagement through training and coaching staff. I worked in three stores progressing from Supervisor to Deputy Manager working with and having managerial responsibility for teams of up to 30 people.

Gardener & Groundworker from 1998 - 2006

Initially working with a partner to private customers this role evolved to groundwork on new build properties. The key learning from this role was a project's success demands team cohesion, and this is made from individuals' commitment and accountability.

# **EDUCATION**

3 month full-time remote coding bootcamp with Makers Academy in 2016

A fast paced and intensive course in software development. The course focused on Agile methodologies, pair programming and TDD. It was taught primarily using Ruby, RSpec, Capybara and Rails with a continual emphasis on using the Single Responsibility Principle and object oriented structuring of programs. I completed the course remotely and while working part-time at weekends. This was very demanding but a worthwhile and rewarding experience.

HND in Multimedia at Canterbury Christ Church, 2002 - 2004

Exploring the role and impact of digital technologies in motion and interactive design.